

Profile

Senior student in the Software Engineering Technology program at the Oregon Institute of Technology. 4 years of experience developing, debugging, and testing full stack projects in both C++ and C# using Microsoft Visual Studio. Transitioning from 11 year career in army aviation, maintaining helicopters.

I aspire to be as proficient and precise in software development as I was in aircraft maintenance.

Summary

Seeking an internship position as a Software Engineer.

- Software Engineering student
 - o Graduating June 2018
 - o Currently 3.8/4.0 GPA
- Proficient in C++

- Proficient in C#
- Experience in SQL
- Experience with Visual Studio
- Experience with Full Stack development

Graduation:

June 2018

3.8/4.0

Education

Oregon Institute of Technology (Oregon Tech)

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering Technology Minor: Applied Mathematics

Academic Recognition:

- Phi Theta Kappa Honors Society
- President's List Multiple Awards
- Dean's List Multiple Awards
- Honor Roll Multiple Awards
- Envision Global International Scholar Laurette Program
- Rhode & Schwarz Engineering Competition 2016
 - o 1st Place Team in United States
 - o 2nd Place Team in International Finals

Classes:

- Computer Science Series C++
- Object Oriented Programing C++

GPA:

- Data Structures C++
- Software Testing Python
- Design Patterns C#
- GUI Programming C#
- Junior Project C#, SQL
- Database Systems & Design SQL
- Statistics & Probability Python

Senior Project – Aviation Maintenance Management System:

Currently developing a web based, version of the army's unit level logistic software – aviation (ULLS-A). This project utilizes ASP.NET Core 2.0, a multi-platform development framework as well as Microsoft SQL Server to construct a full-stack product. Some key product features include the following: multiple user roles, multiple aircraft support, scheduled inspections, unscheduled maintenance, and flight records. This project utilizes NUnit testing and log4net event logging to ensure proper functionality.

Junior Project – Movie Inventory Management Database:

Team based project utilizing ASP.NET Core multi-platform development framework connected to a SQL database. Online accessible movie inventory system, which allows users to keep track of all their movies whether in electronic or physical media. Provides services such as lending of physical media, owner ratings, storage location, and other notes. Pulls information from the Online Movie Database (OMDB) API to display movie posters, plot summaries, rotten tomatoes ratings, and cast listings for all user's movies. Multiple sort and view options for inventory.



Work Experience

L3 Vertex Aerospace

2010 - 2012

H-60 Technical Inspector:

Army contract field team assignment in Afghanistan in support of all H-60 model aircraft (Blackhawk).

- Inspected aircraft for any and all deficiencies.
- Initiated/closed aircraft phase maintenance inspection.
- Created excel forms for rigging procedures to validate aircraft rig.
- Created excel forms for fuel system test procedures to validate fitness of the fuel system.
- Created excel weekly status form for tracking all aircraft, work orders, and employee hours.
- Created excel based aircraft phase packet to track all documents related to each aircraft phase conducted.
- Ensured all aircraft components documentation was on file.
- Ensured all aircraft components were replaced when approaching or exceeding their life expectancy.
- Ensured all maintenance was conducted in accordance with applicable technical manuals.
- Inspected all mechanics work for completeness and accuracy.
- Ensured all follow-up maintenance requirements were documented.
- Approved airworthiness of aircraft.
- Authorized and added new users in the maintenance management software.

Aviation Radio Inc. (ARINC)

2008 - 2010

UID Lead/SME

Unique Identification (UID) Subject Matter Expert (SME)

- Generated 2-dimensional data matrices (UID tags) for United States Army aircraft components.
- Printed UID tags on triple-layered adhesive tape using CO2 laser printers.
- Registered UID tags for the aircraft components in the national UID registry.
- Generated, printed, and issued UID tags for tool room management software (TRMS), aviation life support
 equipment (ALSE), and arms room management software (ARMS).
- Assisted in training the users of the various inventory management software systems.

Tennessee Department of Corrections

2008 - 2008

Correctional Officer:

Central Control Correctional Officer at the Charles Bass Correctional Complex Annex

- Maintained accountability of correctional officer duty equipment for entire facility.
- Logged the movement of inmates throughout day-to-day operations (i.e. work release, temporary transfers, counselor meetings, etc.).
- Created a Microsoft access database to track inmate movements and cell/bunk assignments more easily.
- Confirmed inmate counts between inmate tracking system and barracks officers.

Military Experience

United States Army 2001 – 2010

H-60 Aircraft Technician:

Aircraft technician for all H-60 model aircraft (Blackhawk).

- Performed inspection procedures to identify deficiencies.
- Logged aircraft faults using maintenance management software.
- Performed maintenance procedures to correct aircraft faults.
- Performed servicing procedures to prevent component failures.
- Documented flight records in aircraft logbook.